joost.com 2011-06-23

# Joost

#### Revision Date: August 2010

Your privacy is very important to us. We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use protect, and disclose personal information and log information when you use the Joost website at www.joost.com ("Site"); or any other services, features, tools, software, or applications provided by or through the Site, including the Joost browser plug-in and the Joost Application for the Apple® iPhone®, iPod touch® and iPadTM, (collectively "Services").

This Privacy Policy answers the following questions:

  * What information do we collect about you and how do we use it?
  * Will we share your personal information with third parties?
  * What security measures do we take to safeguard your personal information?
  * Who can I contact if I have any questions about this Privacy Policy?

By using the Site or Services you consent to this Privacy Policy. We may sell the personal information that you supply to us and we may work with other third party businesses to bring selected retail opportunities to our members via direct mail, email and telemarketing. 

## Managing Your Information Preferences

You can always review, correct, update, or change your personal information, or opt out of our direct marketing efforts, by changing the relevant setting in your Joost profile or account (if available), or by e-mailing us at [privacy@joost.com](mailto:privacy@joost.com). If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please e-mail us at [privacy@joost.com](mailto:privacy@joost.com).

## Information We Collect

### Registration and Your Personal Profile

When you register with the Site or the Service, you provide us with certain personal information, such as a username (which may or may not be your real name), email address, gender, zip/postal code and date of birth. The decision to provide this information is optional. However, if you choose not provide the requested information, you may not be able to use certain features of the Site or Services.

When you use the Site or the Services, you will have the option of setting up a personal profile by providing general information about yourself, the URL of your website, address of your blog and a mood message. Additionally, when using the Site or the Services, you will have the option to form relationships, send messages to your friends and other users, perform searches and queries, form groups, add applications, comment on particular content, and transmit information through various channels.

### Cookies

Like many websites, we employ "cookies" in certain areas of the Site to allow us to provide information which is targeted to your interests and to make your online experience more convenient. Cookies are small bits of electronic information that a website sends to a visitor's browser and are stored on the visitor's hard drive. We use cookies for the following purposes:

  * to store a user's log-in identity so that your session won't expire unless you actively log out
  * to keep a record of the programming or advertisements you were watching when you last left the Site
  * to keep a record of any widgets or other additional applications that you have installed.

Certain third parties will also place and read cookies in your browser. Further information on this can be found below in the section "Third Parties Who Collect And Receive Your Information".

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however, if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Site or the Services. For further information on cookies and how to disable cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/). 

### Log Information

We also keep track of your interaction with the Site, the Services, and other users. Specifically, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit the Site or Services. This information includes your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and version, which features you use and when and how long you use them, what programming and advertising you view and share with friends and how long you view it, your browsing history on the Site and the Services (including any links that you may click within the Site or the Services), your search history, and any social connections you have (i.e., your friends and the groups you have joined).

### Slurping

You will have the opportunity to connect with friends from your other networks, such as AOL, Gmail, LinkedIn, Hotmail, Netlog and Yahoo.

The Site will identify the email addresses of the friends in your other networks, and if any of these friends are already Joost® users, we will offer you the opportunity to connect as friends on Joost®, and if you choose to do so, a friend request will be sent by email. If any of your friends are not Joost® users, we will enable you to invite those friends to join Joost®. You will be able to select those friends in your other networks that you wish to invite (if any), and Joost will send one email on your behalf to each of these friends inviting them to visit the Site and register as a Joost® user. If any of your friends respond to your invitation, and subsequently register as Joost® users, you will offered the opportunity to connect as friends on Joost®. If you choose to connect, a friend request will be sent by email.

After this process is complete, and any email invitation(s) have been sent, your friends' email addresses will be deleted from our servers (unless they have registered separately as Joost® users). We will not retain or use these email addresses for any purpose whatsoever, and will not contact your friends or create any connections unless you ask us to.

If your email address appears in anyone else's network, Joost may use your email address for the purposes described above.

### Children's Privacy

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. By using our Site or Services, you promise that you are at least 13 years old. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records. In addition, we recommend that minors 13 years of age or older ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet.

## Information We Use

As a general matter, we use the information that you provide to us to process your user registration, and to provide, enhance and personalize the Site and the Services; and we use the information automatically collected by our servers to monitor and analyze how users use the Site and the Services, and to maintain and improve the Site and the Services. We may also sell the personal information that you supply to us and we may work with other third party businesses to bring selected opportunities to our members based on information we gather from you, via direct mail, email and telemarketing. 

### Email address

If you register with the Site or the Services, we may use your email address for the following purposes:

  * to send you email newsletters that keep you updated about the programming on the Site;
  * to send you other email communications that keep you updated about Joost Features and other functionality of the Site, including, information about available upgrades, functionality and/or features,
  * to ask you to participate in surveys that help us make the Site and the Services better,
  * to respond to or confirm your requests or activity on the Site,
  * to notify you of activity initiated by your friends, or members of groups that you have joined (i.e., to notify you if someone wishes to add you as a friend, or if someone sends you a message, or wishes to share a video with you),
  * to notify you of the existence of other Joost® users who have similar tastes to you,
  * to notify you of service issues and unusual account actions (e.g. password resets),
  * to notify and warn you of inappropriate conduct, and if necessary, to inform you of the suspension or deletion of your account.
  * To deliver advertisements and promotions from third parties that we feel may be of interest to you, based on the information we have gathered from you.

By registering with the Site or the Services, you consent to receiving these communications, but have the right to unsubscribe from receiving future emails at any time (see below).

### Other Personal Information

We may use personal information that you provide, or that we learn about you, to:

  * provide recommendations on programming that we think will be interesting to you based on your previous viewing history,
  * ensure that the advertisements you see as part of your use of the Site and the Joost Features are those that we think will be interesting to you based on your previous viewing history, location, age and gender, 
  * personalize the Site to better reflect your particular interests,
  * attribute your comments, ratings and other contributions to you,
  * maintain your social connections (e.g. your friends and groups),
  * suggest new social connections (e.g. by informing you of the existence of other users having similar tastes to yours, and vice versa) and
  * otherwise improve your use of the Site and the Joost Features

By providing personal information, you consent to the use and sharing of your information with third parties for marketing purposes. We will also use this information to help us quickly and efficiently respond to inquiries and requests, and otherwise enhance our service offering for our users.

### Messaging

Additionally, we, and other users that control the groups that you join, will be able to send you messages on or through the Site or the Services, in particular through the "JoostFeed" on your dashboard. These messages may relate to updates on programming or other special events, or may relate specifically to events within your groups. You will have the ability to manage your receipt of these types of messages through your personal settings on the Site or the Services.

### Unsubscribe

If, at any point in time, you are not interested in receiving emails or other announcements from us, you will be able to "opt-out" by clicking on the specified link in any given email communication, by modifying your personal settings on the Site, or by emailing us at [privacy@joost.com](mailto:privacy@joost.com). Please note that you cannot unsubscribe from certain correspondence from us, including messages relating to your account. To unsubscribe from receiving emails from a particular third party, you will be able to "opt-out" by clicking on the specified link in any given email communication. Unsubscribing from one party’s advertisements will not unsubscribe you from receiving emails from other third parties. 

## Sharing of Information

We may sell or rent your email address or any of your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. We will also share your information in the following ways.

### With Other Users

Your profile information will be available to other users of the Site or the Services. You can elect not to have your profile made public using the "Public Profile" check box in your profile settings.

We will publish information regarding your activity on the Site and your use of the Services in the "JoostFeed" on your dashboard, your friends' dashboards and any groups to which you belong, via RSS feeds to which your friends and members of your groups can subscribe, and via a public feed on the home page of the Site. You can elect not to have your activities published using the "Stealth Mode" check box in your profile settings.

All information that you post or share through your use of the Site or the Services, such as your personal profile, comments, messages, favorite programming, or other information, is done at your own risk. Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information in your profile or when posting comments, messages, favorite programming, or other items, this information may become publicly available.

### As Aggregated Data

We may use your personal information to provide analyses of our users in the aggregate to prospective partners, investors and other third parties. We will also share statistical and demographic information about our users and their use of the Site and the Services with suppliers of advertisements and programming. We may also disclose and otherwise use de-identified information about users. None of the above would include anything that could be used to identify you in the offline world or to discover individual information about you.

### With Service Providers

We may from time to time use third parties to manage portions of the Site or the Services, manage the administration and delivery of advertisements, facilitate our business (e.g. by hosting our servers), manage communications with you, conduct advertising or other audits, conduct surveys, or otherwise provide services to us in connection with the Site or the Services. Where these third parties process information on our or your behalf, we require these third parties to comply with the provisions of this Privacy Policy, to the extent applicable, and require that they maintain high levels of security and do not use your information for any purpose other than to provide their services to us. If these third parties need to collect personally identifiable information or personal data direct from you, we require them to do so under the terms of an effective and publicly available privacy policy (see below - Third Parties Who Collect and Receive Your Information). Joost is not responsible for their compliance with such a policy.

### With our Affiliated Companies

We will share personal information with affiliated companies, and in particular, with our affiliates in the US and the UK to enable them to provide elements of the Site or the Services to you in those territories. The sections below headed "Using Your Personal Information In Other Countries" and "EU Safe Harbor Compliance" provide more information in this regard. Your personal information may also go to other third parties for marketing purposes, based on the information we have gathered from you.

### As Otherwise Required

We will share personal information we collect from you if we believe it is reasonably necessary to make available the Site and the Services, legally required, or otherwise permitted by you. For example:

  * _Protection of rights._ We will share personal information if we have a good faith belief that (i) access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process anywhere in the world, such as a court order or subpoena, or a request by law enforcement or governmental authorities, (ii) such action is appropriate to enforce the Terms of Service for the Site or the Services, including any investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) such action is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues associated with the Joost Features, or (iv) such action is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of Joost, its employees, users of the Joost Features or others.
  * _Asset transfers._ If we become involved in a merger, acquisition or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of our or our affiliates' assets or voting securities, user information, including personal information collected from you through your use of the Site and the Services, may be included in the transferred assets or securities. If this occurs, your personal information would remain subject to this Privacy Policy.

## Third Parties Who Collect and Receive Your Information

### Google Analytics

The Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to help measure and analyze how users use the Site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use the information transmitted to them for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for us and providing other services relating to Site activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, where such third parties process the information on behalf of Google, and where third parties wish to use the information to market products or services to you. Google will not associate your IP address or other information with any other data held by them, or otherwise try to discover your identity.

Google's use of this data is governed by the Google Analytics Terms of Service ([www.google.com/analytics/tos.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/tos.html)) and Privacy Policy ([www.google.com/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/privacy.html)).

### Facebook Connect

If you have a Facebook account, Joost allows you to log in using Facebook Connect ("Connect"), a Facebook, Inc. application that enables the Site to work just like the platform applications you find on Facebook.com ("Facebook"). Once you allow the Site to connect with Facebook, you will be able to use your Facebook login information to log into the Site, and you will be able to publish your activity on the Site to your Facebook profile. Whenever to do anything on the Site that you might want to publish to Facebook, such as watching or commenting on a video, we will ask you whether you want to publish that activity on your Facebook news feed. We will not generate or publish any Facebook news feed and/or other stories about actions you take on the Site without your permission. Additionally, by using Connect, you permit the Site to: access Facebook information related to you (including your profile information, friends, and privacy settings) so you can use your Facebook information on the Site, and so that we can help improve your use of the Site and the Joost Features (for example, by recommending programming or delivering advertising that we think will be of most interest to you); and allow you to interact with your Facebook friends on the Site. In order to make Connect possible, you agree to allow Facebook to check your Facebook cookies when you are visiting the Site, and allow Facebook to receive information concerning the actions you take on the Site (which we will only send with your permission). The information shared with Facebook will be transmitted to and stored by Facebook on servers in the United States. In the event you no longer want the Site to publish stories about you, or want to otherwise limit the ways in which the Site interacts with your Facebook account, you can always disable this feature by changing your application settings in Facebook.

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by Joost through your Facebook Connect login, however, your activities on Facebook are covered by the Facebook privacy policy and other terms of use ([www.facebook.com/terms.php](http://www.facebook.com/terms.php); [www.facebook.com/policy.php](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php)). 

### Ad Network and Ad Serving

We also work with Adconion which sells advertising across a variety of different websites, including the Site – this type of company is known as an ad network.

In order to ensure that you receive advertising that is likely to be of most interest to you, Adconion may need to place and read cookies on your computer, and may need to collect information from you, including your IP address, your browser type and version, and your computer's operating system. The purposes for which Adconion collects and use this information is set out in detail in its privacy policy, which you are advised to read on <http://www.adconion.com/us/privacy-policy.html>. This privacy policy also provide details of how you can "opt out" (i.e. how you can elect not to have these companies collect any information from you) on <http://www.adconion.com/us/privacy-policy/the-adconion-cookie.html>.

### Third Party Applications

We, and third parties, may from time to time make small software applications – that we sometimes call "widgets" – available for your use on or through the Site. These applications may separately access, and allow a third party to view, your identifiable information, such as your name, your username, your computer's IP Address or other information such as what you are watching during any given session, and any cookies that you may previously have installed or that were installed for you by a third party software application or website. Additionally, these applications may ask you to provide additional information directly to third parties. Third party products or services provided through these applications are not owned or controlled by Joost. You are encouraged to read the terms of use and other policies published by such third parties on their websites or otherwise before you use such applications.

By using the Site and the Services, you consent to the processing of data about you by us, Google, Facebook, Adconion or other third parties in the manner set out above.

This Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices of third party websites and service providers. Although we encourage third parties to adopt and follow their own privacy policies, we are not responsible for their collection and use of your personal information. You should refer to the privacy policies and statements of other websites or contact the respective webmasters of those websites to obtain information regarding their information collection, use and disclosure policies.

## Security

We take many precautions to keep your personal information secure from unauthorized access, such as internal corporate policies to limit access to systems that store your personal information. However, no data transmission over the Internet or other network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect information transmitted on or through the Site or Services, we cannot and do not guarantee the security of any information you transmit on or through the Site or Services, and you do so at your own risk. We continue to store your personal information for so long as it is necessary to provide you our service and periodically destroy old personal information in accordance with our company policies, including when it is no longer necessary in order to offer you the same high quality service. In most cases, we will keep one archival copy of your information to allow us to comply with laws or respond to legal processes.

## Processing in the United States

Please be aware that your personal information and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province, or country. If you are located outside of the United States, please be advised that we process and store all information in the United States. The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location. By using our Site or the Services, you agree that the collection, use, transfer, and disclosure of your personal information and communications will be governed by the applicable laws in the United States.

## EU Safe Harbor Compliance

Our US affiliates adhere to the European Safe Harbor principles as set forth by the United States Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personally identifiable information collected from citizens of the European Union. For more information, please visit [www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor).

## Terms of Service / Notification of Changes

Your use of the Site and the Services, and any dispute that may arise from such use, is subject to this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Service and the End User License Agreement applicable to the Joost® browser plug-in, and all of their respective dispute resolution provisions, including limitation on damages and choice of law.

## Privacy Policy Changes

From time to time, we may change this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will inform you by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Those changes will go into effect on the Revision Date shown in the revised Privacy Policy. Your continued use of our Site or Services constitutes your consent to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

## Questions? Contact Us

It is extremely important to us that your privacy is treated with the utmost respect. If you have any concerns, questions, or ideas on how we can do a better job at this while offering our unique personalized television service, please let us know by emailing [privacy@joost.com](mailto:privacy@joost.com)
